# **Ashish Kumar**

www.linkedin.com/in/axeish www.github.com/axeish

+1(857) 415-7534 kumar.as@huskv.neu.edu 17B Smith Street, Boston

Web Developer specializing in front-end development. Experience with all stages of the development and well-versed in programming languages including Javascript, Python with current focus on React and Angular, background in Graphic Design.

## **EDUCATION**

## Northeastern University, Boston, MA

Jan 2015-present

- Master of Science in Computer Science
- Graduate Coursework: Network Security, Program Design Paradigm, Web Development, Algorithms, Human Computer Interaction, Database Management, Managing Software development.

## Visvesvaraya Technological University, Bengaluru, India

Sept 2007-May 2011

(Expected: May 2017)

- Bachelor of Engineering in Computer Science and Engineering
- Undergraduate Coursework: Operating Systems, Databases, Algorithms, Programming Languages, Software Engineering, Computer Architecture, Language Processors, Computer Network, Theory of Computation,

#### **EXPERIENCES**

Teaching Assistant, Northeastern University, Boston, MA

Jan 2017 - Apr 2017

TA for Managing Software Development (CS5500 Spring 17) taken by Prof. Michael Weintraub

### Internet Protocol OS Engineering Intern, Ericsson, San Jose, CA

Jan 2016 - Aug 2016

Developed Yvcloud, a tool to automate developer workflow including building VMware cloud topologies, keys generation, image installation and configuration setup for each node using Python

### Software Engineer, Aricent, Gurgaon, India

Aug 2011- June 2014

- Integrated Regression and Traffic tests into existing Python automation framework for media access gateway and automated new scenarios that conforms to H248/MEGACO Architecture
- Implemented supporting features and performed debugging for Voice over IP media access gateway controller

#### **SKILLS**

Front-End Web JavaScript(including React, AngularJS, Gulp.js, NodeJS), CSS3, HTML5, Bootstrap

Back-End Web Python, MySQL, Mongodb

**Tools** Eclipse, Adobe Creative Suite, Webstorm GIT, AWS, Photoshop, Illustrator, Wireshark Others Networks TCP/IP, UDP, VoIP, ITU-T-H.248, Cryptography

### **ACADEMIC PROJECTS**

Media Licensing Lab

(Java, Angular JS,

(AngularJS, CSS)

MvSOL)

: Developed an online portal that will enable the students to send invites to any -musician or band to upload their compositions with associated metadata for future licensing. The project would be the first licensing lab run by students in USA

Union Capital Boston prototype

Developed a mobile friendly web interface for a non-profit organization *Union Capital* Boston after evaluating the interface with continuous user feedback through iterative interview session and brainstorming ideas based on material design

Secure Instant Messenger (Python, AES, RSA, SRP

Proposed and implemented a secure instant messaging system using the Secure Remote Protocol (SRP) for client server remote authentication

Ashart Website (HTML5, CSS3,JS) Responsive project that works on Artsy API to get detailed information of famous artists and their artwork. The application also let users search for art or artist by keyword

Spaceship Game (Python)

Developed an interactive single player shooting game using concepts of Physics, Python and Object Oriented Programming

# Extra-Curricular activities:

- Worked as freelance graphic designer and developed designs for various emerging startups &university events
- Won awards and recognition in graphic designing, sketching, illustration and crafting